Inventory of the Miguel Aroche Parra papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Copies of articles in Excelsior, Septiembre and other publications, 1970s on MAUS and Coalition of the Left (Box-folder 29: 4)
- Documents on MAUS and Coalition of the Left, 1970s (Box-folder 29: 5)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1982 (Box-folder 29: 6)
- Articles and Manifestos for POCM and expulsion from PCM, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 29: 7)
- POCM documents, 1950s (Box-folder 29: 8)
- Writings on agrarian reform and cocoa production, undated (Box-folder 29: 9)
- Writings from PCM and POCM and various issues, 1950-2000 (Box-folder 29: 10)
- Copies of articles in El Sol de Acapulco, 1990s (Box-folder 29: 11-12)
- Copies of articles in Excelsior and el Sol de Acapulco, 1980s (Box-folder 30: 1)
- MAUS documents and copies of Excelsior articles, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 30: 2)
- Miscellaneous documents, 1970s (Box-folder 30: 3)
- MAUS documents and PRD, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 30: 4)
- Miscellaneous writings on Guerrero 1980s and candidacy for Diputado Federal, 1988 (Box-folder 30: 5)
- Congreso Constituyente of PCM, 1996 (Box-folder 30: 6)
- Documents on Trotskyism, 1940-1980 (Box-folder 30: 7)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1990s (Box-folder 30: 8)
- Various writings on crime and violence in Mexico, 1950-1980 (Box-folder 30: 9)
- Copies of articles and PRD documents, 2000s (Box-folder 30: 10)
- PPS Correspondence, 1960s (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Writings and documents on 1988 elections (Box-folder 31: 2)
- Copies of articles, 2000s (Box-folder 31: 3)
- Copies of articles, 1940s (Box-folder 31: 4)
- Writings and columns on Guerrero, 1980s (Box-folder 31: 5)
- Undated account of 1968 Tlatelolco massacre (Box-folder 31: 6)
  Includes correspondence with Lazaro Cárdenas, 1962.
- Boletin of CEMOS, 1984; La Crisis magazine, 1996; Copies of Excelsior articles, 2000s; PRD ephemera, 2000s (Box-folder 31: 7)
- Presentation to the II National Agrarian Conference, undated (Box-folder 31: 8)
- Correspondence and articles in Excelsior, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 31: 9)
- Documents on Sahrawi Arab Democratic Republic, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 10)
- “Volver a imaginar el socialismo” 1991; Writings and correspondence on government of Guerrero, 1980s (Box-folder 31: 11)
- Writings on guerrillas in Guerrero and political arrests, 1970s; MAUS documents, 1979-1980; Ferrocarril labor, 1980s (Box-folder 31: 12)
- Miscellaneous political documents, from 1960s to 1970s, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 31: 13)
- Copies of articles in El Sol de Guerrero, 1980s (Box-folder 31: 14)
- Writings on corruption in government and clergy, austerity measures, and economic crisis, 1980s (Box-folder 31: 15)
- Prison Correspondence, 1963 (Box-folder 31: 16)
- Writings and pamphlets on crisis in left, Afghanistan, and formation of Coalition of Left, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 31: 17)
- Miscellaneous publications, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Documents on fraud, corruption, and human rights, 1990s (Box-folder 32: 2)
- Writings on Communism and PCM, Clergy, and development, 1940-1980 (Box-folder 32: 3)
- Copies of articles, 1980s (Box-folder 32: 4)
- 1993 Excelsior article; “Tribuna a la Juventud” pamphlet, 1980 (Box-folder 32: 5)
- PRD documents, 1990s (Box-folder 32: 6)
- POCM documents, 1950s (Box-folder 32: 7)
- Miscellanous documents, 1990s (Box-folder 32: 8)
- Ephemera and pamphlets, 1980s (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Writings on agriculture in Guerrero, 1940s; PRD documents, 1990s (Box-folder 32: 10)
- Miscellaneous documents on Chile, education, and ferrocarrileros, 1970s (Box-folder 32: 11)
- Miscellanous documents on PRD, PMS, and constitutional reforms, undated (Box-folder 32: 12)
- PRD documents, 1990s; Correspondence 1950s; Miscellanous articles and documents on PRI (Box-folder 32: 13)
- PPS documents, 1960s (Box-folder 32: 14)
- Miscellanous documents and ephemera on political prisoners and ferrocarrilero strike, 1960-1980 (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Documents on book, “El Che, Jenaro y las Guerrillas,”, undated (Box-folder 33: 2)
- MAUS documents, 1980s (Box-folder 33: 3)
  Includes articles on land and poverty.
- Biographical information on Miguel Aroche Parra, undated (Box-folder 33: 4)
- Empty (Box-folder 33: 5)
- “Militancia en el Partido Comunista” – biographical work on Parra, undated (Box-folder 33: 6)
- Newspaper clippings from 1990s (Box-folder 33: 7)
- MAUS, PPS, and MOS documents, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 33: 8)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 33: 9)
- PRD Platform, 2001 (Box-folder 33: 10)
- XXIV Plenary Session of MAUS, 1970s (Box-folder 33: 11)
- “El Ultraizquierdismo, Caballo de Troya del Imperialismo”, 1975 (Box-folder 33: 12)
- “Guerrero: imagines de ayer,”, undated (Box-folder 33: 13)
- Correspondence after release from prison, 1960s (Box-folder 33: 14)
- Documents on rural normalista school Ayotzinapa and indigenous issues, 1960s (Box-folder 33: 15)
- Essay on Genaro Vazquez Rojas, undated (Box-folder 33: 16)
- Documents and correspondence on imprisonment and ferrocarrileros, 1960s (Box-folder 34: 1)
- POCM documents, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 34: 2-3)
- Documents on 1990s and 2000s elections and PRD (Box-folder 34: 4)
- POCM documents, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 34: 5-6)
- Draft of biography of Miguel Parra written by brother, Fernando, 1992 (Box-folder 34: 7)
- Copies of articles, 1970s (Box-folder 34: 8-9)
- Political writings on Church, minimum wage, and normalistas, 1940s; MAUS documents 1970s and Haiti solidarity and other international issues, 1980s (Box-folder 34: 10)
- Empty (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Poetry, 1970s (Box-folder 35: 2)
- Writings on books and libraries, 1990s (Box-folder 35: 3)
- Documents on Guerrero, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 35: 4)
- FPN, ADN, and ADESE Documents, 1990s (Box-folder 35: 5)
- MAUS documents, 1970s; Other misc. political writings, 1980s (Box-folder 35: 6)
- Copies of articles in El Sol de Acapulco, 1990s (Box-folder 35: 7)
- Poetry, 1980s (Box-folder 35: 8)
- PRD documents, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 35: 9)
- PRD documents, international relations (Cuba and Iraq), 1990s (Box-folder 35: 10)
- Plenary Session of PCM, 1979 May 14 (Box-folder 35: 11)
- Copies of articles on PPS, MAUS, PRD (Box-folder 35: 12)
- Copies of articles in Excelsior, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 35: 13)
- Copies of articles in Excelsior, 1977-1979, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 35: 14)
- ADN docs 2000s; Writings on Che, 1990s; MAUS documents, 1970s (Box-folder 35: 15)
- Miscellaneous political writings on revolution and Marxism, 1930s to 1970s; Poetry 1930s to 1980s (Box-folder 36: 1)
- Draft of “El Che, Genaro y la Guerillas” (1974); Poetry, 1960s-1970s (Box-folder 36: 2)
- POCM documents, 1950s (Box-folder 36: 3)
- Miscellaneous political papers, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 36: 4)
- Correspondence, 1950s; Political papers, 1980s (Box-folder 36: 5)
- “Procuraduria Social de la Montaña”, 1987 May (Box-folder 36: 6)
- List of books from Libreria Nacional (Box-folder 36: 7)
- Poetry, 1960s and 1970s; Notes on work of Elena Poniatowska, 2007 (Box-folder 36: 8)
- Miscellaneous political papers, 1980s (Box-folder 36: 9)
- Papers on Libreria Nacional; Miscellaneous political papers, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 36: 10)
- Poetry, 1960s and 1970s; Political writing, 1980s to 1990s; PCM papers, 1940s (Box-folder 36: 11)
- Correspondence and writings on Guerrero, 1970s (Box-folder 37: 1)
- Copies of articles and correspondence, 1970s; Chilean solidarity papers (Box-folder 37: 2)
- Programa Regional de la Montaña de Guerrero, 1983 (Box-folder 37: 3)
- Documents on imprisonment, 1960s; PCM documents, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 37: 4)
- Documents on Vietnam, China (Asia) and 1958-1959 ferrocarrilero strikes (Box-folder 37: 5)
- PRD documents, 1990s; Copies of articles in El Sol de Acapulco, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 37: 6)
- Copies of articles, 1978 (Box-folder 37: 7)
- Notes on Marx’s Capital, 1954 (Box-folder 37: 8)
- Notes on works by Elena Poniatowska and book “El Che, Genaro y la Guerillas” (Box-folder 37: 9)
- Poetry, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 37: 10)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 38: 1)
- Articles, 1990s (Box-folder 38: 2)
- Newspaper clippings on Acapulco, PRD 2000s; PPS Documents, 1960s; PCM documents, 2000s; Articles, 1980s (Box-folder 38: 3)
- Copies of articles published in El Sol de Acapulco, 1985, 1994 (Box-folder 38: 4)
- Newspaper clippings and speech, 1987, on Cuahtemoc Cardenas presidential run (Box-folder 38: 5)
- Speech by Parra to electoral college, 1979 (Box-folder 38: 6)
- ADN documents, 2000s; 1991 PRD documents (Box-folder 38: 7)
- POCM and PCM documents, 1940-1950 (Box-folder 38: 8)
- PRD and ADN documents, 1990s and 2000s; Copies of Articles, 2000s; 1988 documents on huelga at UNAM (Box-folder 38: 9)
- “Procuraduria Social de la Montaña :Primera Reunion Ordinaria del Consejo Technico”, 1987 June 9 (Box-folder 38: 10)
- Copies of “Fuego Nuevo” (1980), “El Despertador” (1975-1977); Program from 1st National Assembly of Fuerzas de Izquierda (1977) (Box-folder 38: 11)
- Miscellaneous documents and publications, 1980s (Box-folder 38: 12)
- Articles on Guerrero, 1950-1980 (Box-folder 38: 13)
- Articles and correspondence on Guerrero, PST, MAUS, free trade and Chile, 1970s; Purges of PCM 1940s and 1950s (Box-folder 38: 14)
- Copies of publication, “Politica,”, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 39: 1)
- FPN Documents, 1991-1992; articles on ADESE, 1991; Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1991 (Box-folder 39: 2)
- Debates 2: Perestoika y situacion mundial, 1990 September (Box-folder 39: 3)
- D. Mexico, June 11-June 17 (Box-folder 39: 4)
- Correspondence and copies of articles in El Sol de Acapulco, 1982-1983; List and biographical info of Guerrero poets (Box-folder 39: 5)
- MAUS Documents, 1970s; Newspaper clippings, Noviembre 1949; Documents on Cuauhtémoc Cardenas, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 39: 6)
- Correspondence and copies of articles in El Sol de Acapulco, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 39: 7)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1981-1988; Political documents on Guerrero, 1950-1980 (Box-folder 39: 8)
- Articles in Impar weekly, 1974 (Box-folder 40: 1)
- PRD documents, 1991 (Box-folder 40: 2)
- Misc. documents, 1980s (Box-folder 40: 3)
- Articles and magazines dedicated to Raul Isidro Burgos, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 40: 4)
- Segunda Reunion Ordinaria del Consejo Tecnico, 1987 July 22 (Box-folder 40: 5)
- Procuraduria Social de la Montaña Manual General de Organizacion, 1987 June (Box-folder 40: 6)
- Documents on 1988 elections (Box-folder 40: 7)
- Misc. Documents and ephemera, 1987 (Box-folder 40: 8)
- PRD and FPN documents, 1990s (Box-folder 40: 9)
- PRD documents, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 40: 10)
- FPN and ADESE documents, 1992 (Box-folder 40: 11)
- MAUS and PPS documents, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 40: 12)
- PRD documents, 1994 (Box-folder 40: 13)
- PRD documents, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 40: 14)
- Partidos del Frente Cardenista de Reconstruccion Nacional, 1980s; PRD documents, 1990 (Box-folder 40: 15)
- PSD and PRD documents, 1985-1988; Documents on Venezuela, 1980 (Box-folder 40: 16)
- Drafts and Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 41: 1)
- PT documents, undated (Box-folder 41: 2)
- Articles published in Excelsior, 1982-1987; Correspondence, 1982-1984; PMT documents, undated (Box-folder 41: 3)
- Newspaper clippings, 1990; Copies of articles for Excelsior, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 41: 4)
- PSD documents, 1996; PPS documents, 1989; POCM Correspondence, 1949-1955 (Box-folder 41: 5)
- ADN, ADESE, and PSD documents, 1994-1996; Copies of Articles for Excelsior, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 41: 6)
- PCM Documents, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 41: 7)
- POCM Documents, 1950s; Article clippings, 1980s (Box-folder 41: 8)
- Copies of articles for Excelsior, 1985 (Box-folder 42: 1)
- Copies of articles (various publications), 1979-1991 (Box-folder 42: 2)
- Copies of articles and PRD documents, 1986, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 42: 3)
- Newspaper clippings, 1995; Copies of articles, 1990 (Box-folder 42: 4)
- Articles, 1990 (Box-folder 42: 5)
- PPS and MAUS correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 42: 6)
- Documento Base - IX Encuentro del Foro de Sao Paulo: La Izquierda Frenta al Nuevo Siglo, La Lucha Continua 19-21 February 2000; Articles and Correspondence of Aroche Parra, 1999 (Box-folder 42: 7)
- Documents on Trotskyism, 1980s (Box-folder 42: 8)
- Correspondence of General Amadeo S. Vidales of Guerrero, 1927-1934 (Box-folder 42: 9)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1977-1981 (Box-folder 42: 10)
- Newspaper clippings on POCM, 1951-1952; Letter from Maurilio Beltián, 1975; “La Internacional” publication, 1971; 1966 Boletín Bibliografico; “El Alacrán,”, 1970 October 31 (Box-folder 42: 11)
- Documents on Agrarian reform, 1975-1977; PCM Documents, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 42: 12)
- Copies of articles, 2002-2006 (Box-folder 42: 13)
- Copies of articles in Excelsior, 1980-1990 (Box-folder 43: 1)
- Misc. political documents, 1970s to 1990s on Rural Normal School of Ayotzinapa, Guerrero, PRD and other issues (Box-folder 43: 2)
- MAUS documents, 1975-1979 (Box-folder 43: 3)
- Poetry and music (undated); Copies of articles, 1987-2005 (Box-folder 43: 4)
- Copy of “Socialismo: Revista de Teoría y Política” (December 1990) and PRD documents, 1999 (Box-folder 43: 5)
- PRD documents and ephemera, 1989-2000 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  Includes copies of articles for Excelsior.
- PRD Documents, PCM documents, 1944-1946, 1990 (Box-folder 43: 7)
- Correspondence and other writings while in prison, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 43: 8)
- Circulars, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 44: 1)
- Copies of articles, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 44: 2)
- Circular presented to Jose Lopez Portillo, 1976; Infractructure Program for Nahoa, Mixteca, and Tlapaneca, undated (Box-folder 44: 3)
- Various political documents, POCM documents, 1955, 1980-1996 (Box-folder 44: 4)
- PRD documents, 1991 (Box-folder 44: 5)
- Empty (Box-folder 44: 6)
- Copies of articles, 2003-2004; Other political documents, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 44: 7)
- Misc. political documents, 1981-1991 (Box-folder 44: 8)
- FPN Documents, 1990-1996 (Box-folder 44: 9)
- Copies of articles and correspondence on Excelsior and El Sol de Acapulco, 1995 (Box-folder 44: 10)
- Copies of articles and correspondence on Excelsior and El Sol de Acapulco, 2000 (Box-folder 44: 11)
- FPN Documents and newspaper clippings on Cardenismo; Copies of Articles and Correspondence on Excelsior and El Sol de Acapulco, 1993 (Box-folder 44: 12)
- Photocopies of publication, “28 Poemas de Amor Y Vida,” (Box-folder 44: 13)
- Copies of Corridos by Hernan Laborde; Misc. political documents and ephemera, 1991 (Box-folder 44: 14)
- “Solidaridad” magazine (June 16, 1970); Correspondence with Alejandro Cervantes Delgado (1985); “Acerca el Movimiento Sindical,”, undated (Box-folder 45: 1)
- Documents on Consejo Nacional de Actividades Culturales, 1985 (Box-folder 45: 2)
- Newspaper clippings and documents on PSD and CNT (1987); PCM Correspondence, 1945 (Box-folder 45: 3)
- Copies of various articles for Liberacion, 1981 (Box-folder 45: 4)
- Copies of Articles, 1986-1988; MAUS Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box-folder 45: 5)
- Copies of El Despertador (1976-1977); Puerto (1986) and La Letra y Imagen (1980) (Box-folder 45: 6)
- PCM Correspondence, 1945-1946; Documents from imprisonment, 1965; Chilean solidarity ephemera, 1973 (Box-folder 45: 7)
- PCM Correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 45: 8)
- Various publications, circulars, and newspapers, 1971-1998 (Box-folder 45: 9)
- ADN documents, 1990-2000 (Box-folder 45: 10)
- Copy of script of 19th episode of unnamed production (Box-folder 45: 11)
- PRD documents, 1990; MAUS documents, 1977; Articles, 1999 (Box-folder 46: 1)
- Articles for Excelsior and other publications, 1986-1997 (Box-folder 46: 2)
- Copies of articles published in Excelsior, 1990-1991; Alicia Castañeda Alderete manuscript “El Desarrollo de la Conciencia Cientifica” (undated) (Box-folder 46: 3)
- Notes and writings on book, “El Che, Jenaro y las Guerrillas” and Chilean solidarity documents, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 46: 4)
- Writings from Lecumberri prison, 1962 (Box-folder 46: 5)
- Miscellaneous political documents, 1977-1997 (Box-folder 46: 6)
- Documents on political corruption in Mexico, 1988 (Box-folder 46: 7)
- Copies of articles for Excelsior, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 46: 8)
- Lecumberri imprisonment correspondence and writings, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 46: 9)
- MAUS documents and correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 46: 10)
- Copies of articles for Excelsior, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 47: 1)
- Copies of articles for Excelsior, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 47: 2)
- Articles for Excelsior, 2006 (Box-folder 47: 3)
- Copies of articles in Excelsior, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 47: 4)
- Publications and Ephemera, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 47: 5)
- Various articles on PRD and PSUM, 1982-1990 (Box-folder 47: 6)
- Articles for Excelsior, 1994 (Box-folder 47: 7)
- Documents on MAUS, 1977; PRD 1989; Articles for Excelsior, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 47: 8)
- FPN and ADESE materials, 1992 (Box-folder 47: 9)
- “Principios Elementales del Marxismo”, 1961 (Box-folder 47: 10)
- Copies of articles in Excelsior, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 47: 11)
- PRD documents, 1990 (Box-folder 47: 12)
- Articles published in Excelsior and El Sol de Acapulco, 1978-1997 (Box-folder 47: 13)
- Articles, correspondence, and other materials on PRD and EZLN, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 48: 1)
- Copies of articles for Síntesis, 2000 (Box-folder 48: 2)
- Various circulars and ephemera (Box-folder 48: 3)
- Articles and newspaper clippings, 1944-1950 (Box-folder 48: 4)
- PRD documents, 1991 (Box-folder 48: 5)
- ADESE and PRD documents, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 48: 6)
- Articles for unknown publication, undated (Box-folder 48: 7)
- Copies of articles, 1990-2004 (Box-folder 48: 8)
- Copies of articles, 1983-1995 (Box-folder 48: 9)
- MAUS program, 1977; PRD documents, 1994 (Box-folder 48: 10)
- POCM documents, 1950 (Box-folder 49: 1)
- MAUS documents, 1980 (Box-folder 49: 2)
- Various writings on international relations, 1969-1991 (Box-folder 49: 3)
- “Pactos, Bolsas de Valores y Dinero” by Alicia Castañeda Akderete, 1990 June 5 (Box-folder 49: 4)
- Copies of publications “Por Esto” (1985) and “La Jornada”(1988) (Box-folder 49: 5)
- Copies of Regeneracion, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 49: 6)
- PRD and ADN documents, 1991-1997; Correspondence and writings, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 49: 7)
- Copy of El Despertador, 1976; Political speeches, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 49: 8)
- Speeches, articles, and correspondence on PRD and ADN, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 49: 9)
- Correspondence and articles, 1999 (Box-folder 49: 10)